<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FAQ>
<SECTION id="0" index="14" topicCode="GENERAL2">
<title>Obecné</title>
<QUESTION id="1" index="0">
    <text>Jak určit hodnotu mince?</text>
    <answer>
        <![CDATA[
            <div>
                Hodnota mince se určuje podle několika faktorů. Mezi ně se řadí stáří mince, kov, ze kterého je vyražena a náklad (vzácnost). Množství typů a nominálů mincí je rozsáhlé a existují tak i tisíce let staré mince se zanedbatelnou hodnotou. Naproti tomu jsou i moderní mince, o které je mezi sběrateli velký zájem. Bližší informace naleznete v našem článku nebo nás kontaktujte. Rádi Vám se vším pomůžeme a zodpovíme jakékoliv další dotazy týkající se tématiky.
                <br></br>
                <a href="https://www.aurea.cz" target="_blank">klikněte pro více informací</a>
            </div>
        ]]>
    </answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="2" index="1">
    <text>Jak určit hodnotu bankovky?</text>
    <answer>
        <![CDATA[
            <div style="display: flex; align-items: flex-start; gap: 15px;">
                <div>
                    Hodnota bankovky závisí na jejím stáří, vzácnosti, stavu (grading), nominální hodnotě a poptávce mezi sběrateli. Může být užitečné porovnat bankovku s podobnými kusy na aukcích a v katalozích. Využít můžete náš archiv, nebo nás pro bližší informace kontaktovat.
                </div>
                <img src="https://via.placeholder.com/300" alt="Bankovka" style="max-width: 150px; height: auto; display: block;">
            </div>
        ]]>
    </answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="3" index="2">
<text>Co je grading mincí?</text>
<answer>
        <![CDATA[
            <div>
                <div>
                    Jedná se o proces hodnocení stavu mincí a medailí. Tento proces zahrnuje posouzení různých aspektů předmětu, jako je opotřebení/oběh, způsob ražby a případné poškození. Také vzácnost samotné mince může mít kladný vliv na hodnocení. Existuje několik standardizovaných stupnic, např. Sheldonova stupnice od 1 do 70 bodů, přičemž 1 je nejhorší a 70 nejlepší. V rámci certifikace bude mince umístěna do plastového holderu s popisem a určením zachovalosti. Každá mince má svůj unikátní neopakovatelný kód, pomocí kterého lze určit pravost certifikátu. Nabízíme grading prostřednictvím NGC, bližší informace na grading.
                </div>
                <br></br>
                <img src="https://via.placeholder.com/300" alt="Bankovka" style="max-width: 150px; height: auto; display: block;">
            </div>
        ]]>
    </answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="4" index="3">
<text>Co je grading bankovek?</text>
<answer>Grading bankovek je podobný proces jako grading mincí, zaměřený na hodnocení stavu bankovky. Faktory zahrnují zachovalost papíru, ostrost tisku, přítomnost skvrn, trhlin a dalších vad. Stupnice gradingu bankovek se pohybuje od „Poor“ (špatný) po „Gem Uncirculated“ (perfektní neoběhová). Stejně jako u mincí, spolupracujeme s mezinárodně uznávanou společností PGC, kde můžete využít našich služeb jako jejich obchodních partnerů.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="5" index="4">
<text>Jak se dělá grading mincí?</text>
<answer>Poté co gradingová společnost obdrží minci nebo medaile dojde k posouzení pravosti a stavu. Proces zahrnuje pečlivé zkoumání mince a hodnocení jejích fyzických vlastností. Následně je tato mince porovnávána se stejným tipem a ohodnocena na standardizované stupnici. Výsledkem gradingu je mince označená “gradem” tedy hodnocením nebo mince necertifikovaná. Poté je zapečetěna v ochranném obalu.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="6" index="5">
<text>Kolik stojí grading mincí?</text>
<answer>Cena za grading mincí se liší podle samotné hodnoty mince a rychlosti, s jakou je služba požadována. Nás ceník najdete na – odkaz</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="7" index="6">
<text>Kolik stojí grading bankovek?</text>
<answer>Grading bankovek je obdobně nákladný jako grading mincí. Náklady se pohybují od 10 do 50 USD za bankovku, v závislosti na hodnotě bankovky a požadované rychlosti služby.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="8" index="7">
<text>Co se sbírkou mincí v pozůstalosti?</text>
<answer>Před prodejem sbírky nebo samostatné mince, medaile nebo řádu je vhodné nechat je ocenit odborníkem. Osobní prohlídka je nejlepší pro optimální určení stavu a ceny. Možné je také zaslat fotografie. Mnohé mince mohou mít vysokou sběratelskou hodnotu. V případě zájmu o radu, ocenění nebo prodej zašlete fotografie na info@aurea.cz a na základě emailu Vám poradíme, jak dále postupovat. Více o nás – odkaz</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="9" index="8">
<text>Jak prodat staré mince?</text>
<answer>Možností je několik. Mince, bankovky a odznaky Vám rádi přijmeme do aukce, komisního prodeje nebo je od Vás vykoupíme. Prodej skrze aukci mnohdy vynáší největší zisk, avšak ne všechny sběratelské předměty jsou na zařazení do aukce vhodné. V případě, že nebudete mít zájem o vložení do aukce, nabídneme Vám nejvyšší možnou cenu k výkupu. Často nás navštěvují obchodníci a sběratelé, kteří preferují prodej napřímo. Můžete nás kdykoliv navštívit, případně předem zavolat a domluvit si schůzku (vhodné v případě většího množství předmětů).</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="10" index="9">
<text>Jak prodat staré bankovky?</text>
<answer>Prodej starých bankovek probíhá podobně jako prodej mincí. Lze je nabídnout na aukcích, prostřednictvím přímého prodeje, na online tržištích nebo přímo sběratelům. Stejně jako u mincí, máme v týmu specialistu na Notafilii. Můžete se na něj kdykoliv obrátit.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="11" index="10">
<text>Kde prodat sbírku mincí?</text>
<answer>Sbírku mincí lze prodat napřímo formou výkupu. Nadále je možný komisní prodej za Vámi určenou cenu nebo vložení do aukce. Kontaktovat nás můžete kdykoliv.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="12" index="11">
<text>Kde prodat sbírku bankovek?</text>
<answer>Sbírku bankovek můžete prodat na stejných místech jako sbírku mincí: na numismatických aukcích, ve specializovaných obchodech, na online tržištích nebo přímo sběratelům. I zde platí, že konzultace s odborníkem může zvýšit šance na výhodný prodej. A přesně takového u nás v týmu máme. Zašlete pár fotografií a rádi Vám se vším pomůžeme.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="13" index="12">
<text>Jak začít sbírat mince?</text>
<answer>Srdečně každému novému sběrateli doporučujeme studovat problematiku, než se pustí do samotného sbírání. Numismatika a notafilie je složitá a rozsáhlá disciplína a je proto nutné se nejprve seznámit se základy. Literatura je tak nejlepším přítelem každého začínajícího sběratele (odkaz na eshop). Dobré je určit si jaké období chcete sbírat. Dále se seznámit s určováním samotné mince, čtení opisů a určení stavu. Vhodné jistě bude pro nového sběratele osobně navštívit schůzky místní Numismatické společnosti (ČNS) nebo také nejbližší burzy. V případě dotazů se na nás můžete obrátit.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="14" index="13">
<text>Jak začít sbírat bankovky?</text>
<answer>Začátek sběratelství bankovek je podobný jako u mincí. Vyberte si oblast zájmu, studujte literaturu, navštěvujte burzy a aukce a zapojte se do komunity sběratelů. Naučte se hodnotit stav a autenticitu bankovek.</answer>
</QUESTION>
</SECTION>
<SECTION id="1" index="0" topicCode="GENERAL">
<title>General Questions</title>
<QUESTION id="1" index="0">
<text>What is your return policy?</text>
<answer>Our return policy allows returns within 30 days of purchase. Products must be in their original packaging. Refunds are processed within 3-5 business days.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="2" index="1">
<text>How can I contact customer support?</text>
<answer>You can contact our customer support via phone, email, or live chat. Our team is available from 9 AM to 6 PM every weekday. Response times vary depending on the volume of inquiries.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="3" index="2">
<text>Do you offer gift wrapping?</text>
<answer>Yes, we offer gift wrapping for an additional fee. You can select this option during the checkout process. Our gift wrapping service includes a personalized message.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="4" index="3">
<text>Can I modify my order after it's placed?</text>
<answer>Modifications to orders can be made within one hour of placing the order. Please contact customer support immediately to request changes. After one hour, the order will be processed as is.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="5" index="4">
<text>Where can I find my order history?</text>
<answer>Your order history can be found in your account settings under "Order History". If you are not logged in, please sign in to access this information. If you encounter any issues, contact support.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="6" index="5">
<text>How do I reset my password?</text>
<answer>To reset your password, go to the login page and click on "Forgot Password?". Follow the prompts to enter your email, and you will receive a link to create a new password.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="7" index="6">
<text>What payment methods do you accept?</text>
<answer>We accept various payment methods, including credit cards, PayPal, and bank transfers. You can choose your preferred method during checkout. For security, all transactions are encrypted.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="8" index="7">
<text>Is my personal information secure?</text>
<answer>Yes, we prioritize your security and privacy. We use industry-standard encryption protocols to protect your information. For more details, please review our privacy policy.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="9" index="8">
<text>Do you have a mobile app?</text>
<answer>Yes, our mobile app is available for both iOS and Android. You can download it from the App Store or Google Play. The app offers a user-friendly experience for shopping on the go.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="10" index="9">
<text>What if an item is out of stock?</text>
<answer>If an item is out of stock, you can sign up for restock notifications. We will email you when the item is available again. Alternatively, you can check back regularly on our website.</answer>
</QUESTION>
</SECTION>
<SECTION id="2" index="1" topicCode="SHIPPING">
<title>Shipping Information</title>
<QUESTION id="1" index="0">
<text>What are the shipping options?</text>
<answer>We offer standard, expedited, and overnight shipping options. Standard shipping takes 5-7 business days. Expedited options deliver faster but may incur additional charges.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="2" index="1">
<text>How can I track my order?</text>
<answer>Once your order has shipped, you will receive a tracking number via email. You can use this number on our website to track your package. Tracking information is updated regularly.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="3" index="2">
<text>Do you ship internationally?</text>
<answer>Yes, we ship to selected countries outside the U.S. International shipping rates and delivery times vary by destination. Please check our shipping policy for more details.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="4" index="3">
<text>What should I do if my package is lost?</text>
<answer>If your package is lost, please contact customer support for assistance. We will initiate an investigation with the carrier. You may need to provide your order number and shipping details.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="5" index="4">
<text>Can I change my shipping address after placing an order?</text>
<answer>You can change your shipping address within one hour of placing your order. Please contact our support team to request this change. After this period, we cannot guarantee address updates.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="6" index="5">
<text>Are there shipping fees?</text>
<answer>Shipping fees vary depending on the selected shipping method and your location. Free shipping is offered on orders over a certain amount. You will see the shipping cost during checkout.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="7" index="6">
<text>How long does shipping take?</text>
<answer>Shipping times depend on the method selected at checkout. Standard shipping typically takes 5-7 business days. Expedited shipping options are available for faster delivery.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="8" index="7">
<text>What happens if I missed the delivery?</text>
<answer>If you miss a delivery, the carrier will typically leave a notice. You can arrange for redelivery or pick up your package from the carrier's facility. Please check the notice for instructions.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="9" index="8">
<text>Can I have my order delivered to a PO Box?</text>
<answer>Yes, we can deliver to PO Boxes. Please ensure your shipping address is complete and accurate. Some shipping methods may not be available for PO Box addresses.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="10" index="9">
<text>What should I do if my order arrives damaged?</text>
<answer>If your order arrives damaged, please contact our customer service immediately. We will need photos of the damaged item to process your claim. We strive to resolve these issues quickly.</answer>
</QUESTION>
</SECTION>
<SECTION id="3" index="2" topicCode="PRODUCTS">
<title>Product Information</title>
<QUESTION id="1" index="0">
<text>Are your products guaranteed?</text>
<answer>Yes, all our products come with a satisfaction guarantee. If you're not satisfied, you can return them within the specified return period. Warranty details vary by product.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="2" index="1">
<text>Do you have product recommendations?</text>
<answer>We offer product recommendations based on customer preferences and reviews. You can find these recommendations on our website. For personalized suggestions, contact our support team.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="3" index="2">
<text>Can I see product reviews?</text>
<answer>Yes, you can view product reviews on our website under each product listing. Customers can leave feedback and ratings based on their experiences. Reviews help others make informed decisions.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="4" index="3">
<text>Do you offer samples?</text>
<answer>We offer samples for certain products upon request. Please check the product page for sample availability. Samples are limited to one per customer and may require shipping fees.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="5" index="4">
<text>How do I know if an item is in stock?</text>
<answer>Stock availability is displayed on each product page. If an item is out of stock, you can sign up for restock notifications. We update our inventory regularly to reflect real-time stock levels.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="6" index="5">
<text>Are there size guides available?</text>
<answer>Yes, size guides are available for clothing and accessories. You can find the size guide link on each product page. We recommend checking the size guide to ensure the best fit.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="7" index="6">
<text>What materials are your products made from?</text>
<answer>Our products are made from high-quality materials sourced from reliable suppliers. Each product page includes detailed descriptions of materials used. If you have specific questions, contact us.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="8" index="7">
<text>Can I order custom products?</text>
<answer>Yes, we offer custom products for bulk orders. Please contact our sales team for more information on customization options. Lead times and pricing will vary based on your requirements.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="9" index="8">
<text>What is the best way to care for your products?</text>
<answer>Care instructions are provided with each product. We recommend following these guidelines to maintain the quality and longevity of your items. If you have questions about care, reach out to support.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="10" index="9">
<text>Do you provide product warranties?</text>
<answer>Yes, we provide warranties for certain products. Warranty details are included on the product page. Please review the warranty information for each product before purchase.</answer>
</QUESTION>
</SECTION>
<SECTION id="4" index="3" topicCode="RETURNS">
<title>Return Policy</title>
<QUESTION id="1" index="0">
<text>How do I return an item?</text>
<answer>To return an item, please fill out our return form included with your order. Send the item back to the provided address within the return period. Ensure items are in original condition.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="2" index="1">
<text>Can I return sale items?</text>
<answer>Sale items can be returned unless stated otherwise in the sale policy. Please check the product details for return eligibility on discounted items.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="3" index="2">
<text>What is the return period?</text>
<answer>The return period is 30 days from the date of purchase. Items must be returned within this timeframe to be eligible for a refund or exchange.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="4" index="3">
<text>How long does it take to process returns?</text>
<answer>Returns are processed within 7-10 business days after we receive the returned item. You will receive an email confirmation once your return has been processed.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="5" index="4">
<text>What should I do if I received a defective item?</text>
<answer>If you receive a defective item, please contact our customer service immediately. We will arrange for a replacement or refund based on your preference and our policy.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="6" index="5">
<text>Are return shipping fees covered?</text>
<answer>Return shipping fees are generally the responsibility of the customer unless the return is due to our error. If you receive a wrong or defective item, we will cover return shipping costs.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="7" index="6">
<text>Can I exchange an item?</text>
<answer>Exchanges can be processed for the same item in a different size or color. Please contact customer support for assistance with exchanges. We cannot guarantee availability.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="8" index="7">
<text>What happens if my return is lost in transit?</text>
<answer>If your return is lost in transit, we recommend using a traceable shipping service. Unfortunately, we cannot issue refunds for items that we do not receive. Keep your tracking information.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="9" index="8">
<text>Can I return items after the return period?</text>
<answer>Items returned after the return period may be subject to store credit or a restocking fee. Please check with customer service for eligibility on late returns.</answer>
</QUESTION>
<QUESTION id="10" index="9">
<text>What information do I need to provide for returns?</text>
<answer>You need to provide your order number, the reason for the return, and any relevant details about the item. This information helps us process your return more efficiently.</answer>
</QUESTION>
</SECTION>
</FAQ>